

Joseph Colby

Experienced in both web technologies, and design fundamentals, I am confident that in my ability to excel and exceed in any web design or development position that you have available.

My qualifications include, but are not limited to:

- 4+ years of design and development experience in both real world and educational environments.
- An ability to work under pressure and put in the time needed to complete a project.
- The ability to keep the end user in mind from the beginning of a project to the end.
- Willingness to excel and continue to learn.
- Adaptable to diverse situations and projects while maintaining focus under tight deadlines.

I am confident in my ability to make an immediate and long-term contribution to your company. I would welcome an opportunity to meet with you to discuss my qualifications and candidacy in further detail. In the mean time, I would be happy to answer any questions you may have and look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely, Joseph W. Colby

Phone: 407.252.0550

Email: me@josephcolby.com

Address: Joseph W. Colby 33 Colby Blvd. Oxford, Maine 04270



Joseph Colby

PHP & MySQL
Valid XHTML & CSS
Javascript & JQuery Library
Web Standards and Usability Concepts
Mobile Web Design & Development
Search Engine Optimization Tactics
Rich Media Optimization

2008 - 2010

Full Sail University
Orlando, Florida
Bachelor of Science in Web Design & Development
Valedictorian of Graduating Class

2005-2008

University of Maine Orono Orono, Maine New Media

2007 - Present | Pinetreecountryquilts.com

Site Maintenance and Web Designer/Developer Created content managment system and site. Code Used: PHP, MySQL, CSS, and XHTML.

2007 | Microdyne Outsourcing

Dell Customer Care and Sales Representative Assisted in Sales and Customer Service.

2006 | Microsoft/Volt

Student Technical Representative
Promoted Microsoft Technologies and Products.

Phone: 407.252.0550

Email: me@josephcolby.com

Address: Joseph W. Colby 33 Colby Blvd.

Oxford, Maine 04270



407.252.0550

me@josephcolby.com

Personal Profile

I have a Bachelor of Science degree in Web
Design and Development from Full Sail University,
where I was the Valedictorian of my class and
received and award for Mobile Device
Deployment. I have experience in sales, physical
labor, web technologies, coding, and have the
ability to work well with others.

Work Experience

Pine Tree Country Quilts

Jan 2007 - Present

Susan Harvey
207.827.3876
sharvey@midmaine.com
525 Kirkland Road
Old Town. ME 04468

Web Developer and Designer

- Created the layout, design, and information architecture for www.pinetreecountryquilts.com
- Setup the e-commerce site for selling their products.
- Created a content management system (CMS) for Pine Tree
 Country Quilts to manage their products that they are selling.

Microdyne Outsourcing Inc

Jan 2007 – Aug 2007

Human Resources 207.866.6000 3 Godfrey Drive Orono, Maine 04473

Dell Customer Care Representative

 Contacted customers who recently purchased a Dell computer and ensured that everything was working fine for them.

Outbound and Inbound Sales Representative

- Received inbound calls and called Dell customers to sell them a warranty on their recent computer purchase.
- Up-sold Dell products to prior customers.

Microsoft

Jan 2007 – May 2007

Microsoft Student Partners msp_help@microsoft.com 15885 NE 28^{th.} Suite 100 Bellevue, WA 98008

Student Technical Representative

- Coordinated with other student representatives to bring attention to the new Microsoft products and technologies.
- Represented Microsoft at the University of Maine campus as a Microsoft Student Partner.
- Helped set up sessions with other students on campus to showcase Microsoft's Vista and other products.

Luba Greene 207.743.8972 Main St Suite 11 Oxford, ME 04270

Summer Children's Program Mentor

 I helped coordinate projects and activities for a summer children's program, while maintaining a positive environment for children to learn.

Jeff Ward's Excavation

Jun 2005 – Aug 2008

Jeff Ward 207.583.0964 98 Mutiny Brook Rd. Waterford, ME 04088

Excavation Help

 Assisted with putting in foundations, piping, lawns, and other excavation related work.

Education

Full Sail University

Degree In: BS Web Design and Development
Attended: 2008 - 2010
Address: University Blvd.

Winter Park, FL 32792

University of Maine Orono

Studied: New Media
Attended: 2005 – 2008

Address: The University of Maine

Orono, ME 04469

Campus Activities and Awards

Beta Theta Pi Fraternity (*University of Maine*)

Valedictorian of Web Design and Development Program (*Full Sail University*)

Mobile Device Deployment Award (*Full Sail University*)

Contact Information

Joseph W. Colby

Mobile: 407.252.0550

Email: me@josephcolby.com

Address: 33 Colby Blvd.

Oxford ME, 04270